There he is.
Hey, Andy! Where you been?
It's an all-hands function.
Come here.
I want you to meet Joanie.
Joanie, this is Andy Tyler.
Hello. Hi.
He's my best friend.
We went to Annapolis together.
Nice to meet you, Joanie.
Hey, I got you
one of Larson's stogies.
To our Navy's
next sub skipper.
Thank you.
Lieutenant.
You gonna hoist up a few beers
with the enlisted boys later?
You got it, Griggs.
All right.
Mr. Tyler. Mr. Tyler.
My mom is here visiting.
Can I bring her over
to meet you?
Sure thing, Trigger.
Sure thing.
That's the lieutenant
I was talking about.
Lieutenant Tyler!
Hello there, Prudence,
Louise. Mrs. Dahlgren,
Captain.
Where's your date, Andy?
It's not like you
to arrive stag like this.
I'm afraid I couldn't get one
on such short notice, ma'am.
Captain, could I have
a word with you?
Certainly. Darling,
will you excuse us?
Okay.
Be right back.
I didn't get my boat.
I know.
And with all due respect, sir,
there's only one way
that could have happened.
And that's if you withheld
your recommendation.
That's right.
I just don't think
you're ready.
What do you mean,
I'm not ready?
Sir, I have worked my tail off
on the S-33.
I'm qualified in every area
and then some.
No executive officer
has higher marks than I do,
Captain.
Andy!
You're just not ready
to take on a command
of your own.
Now I've made my decision.
It's done.
Mr. Tyler.
How you doing, sir?
Having a good time?
Hell, yeah, Chief.
How about you?
Looking forward
to getting underway.
I'm a sea dog.
Need some salt, sir.
He torpedoed me, Chief.
Nine months aboard the S-33. . .
doing the best job I know how.
Doing everything once
and then doing it again.
Just to make sure
I didn't miss anything
the first time.
You'll get your chance, sir.
There's other commands
in the Navy.
You knew?
Didn't warn me.
Ain't my place, sir.
CIub secured!
Time to go!
et's go. Get out.
Everyone out.
This club's secured.
Gotta go.
What's the meaning
of this, Sergeant?
You the senior man?
That's right.
I'm the XO of the S-33.
These men have
a 48-hour liberty pass.
No, sir, not no more.
What the hell are those
yard birds doing to my boat?
Looks like a goddamn
Nazi submarine.
Hey, Andy.
This is a fine Navy day.
They wouldn't give me
five minutes to consummate
my marriage. Five minutes!
What's going on here?
Hell if I know.
Put your cover on.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Tyler, call the crew
to quarters.
Aye, Captain.
Quarters! Everybody fall in !
Let's get in formation now!
Let's go! Now! Formation !
Repair Crew 3,
muster with First Lieutenant.
Captain Dahlgren,
all crew members present
and accounted for, sir!
Very well. At ease.
I'm sorry your liberty's
been cut short,
but our schedule's changed.
We have two hours
to get stowed for sea
and set the maneuvering watch.
Mr. Larson,
have your torpedomen. . .
load the tubes
with their four best fish.
Mr. Emmett,
warm up the diesels
and line up a battery charge.
Mr. Tyler, we have dry stores,
ordnance and perishables
to get below decks.
Gentlemen, it's our turn.
That's all.
Attention !
Aye, Captain.
Crew dismissed.
You heard the man.
Stores load.
You got six seconds
to get on your boondockers
and dungarees and turn to.
Mr. Tyler, is this for real,
or is it a drill?
I mean, you know,
"it's our turn,"
what does that mean?
I thought we had
a two-day liberty pass.
What's going on?
I don't know. I don't know,
but I'm gonna find out.
Get your jobs done now.
AII off-going
duty officers,
report to the dock....
Captain Dahlgren,
could you fill me in
on what's going on, sir?
I mean,
we're obviously not going
to the Caribbean station.
No, we're not.
We're going on a special op.
You'll be briefed
with Mr. Emmett and Mr. Larson
once we get underway.
Aye, sir.
Andy, listen to me.
I'm gonna need the very best
from you on this run. . .
regardless of any differences
you may have with me.
Are we clear on that?
Yes, sir.
Good.
Now go find Radioman Wentz
and quietly escort him
to the materiel office.
Mr. Tyler. How are you, son?
I'm fine, Admiral Duke.
What brings you up here?
He does.
That's Lieutenant Hirsch.
He's gonna be
riding your boat.
You're not working for SUBLANT
on this run. Mr. Hirsch
has operational control.
He's the boss.
Anything he wants, he gets.
All right.
Is this him?
Yes, sir.
He'll do.
Thank you, Wentz.
That's all for now.
Lieutenant,
prepare the boat
to get underway.
Aye, sir. Admiral.
Mr. Tyler, please,
don't tell the other guys
I'm half German.
They'll hate me.
Yeah, sure thing, Wentz.
Repair Crew 3,
muster with First Lieutenant.
Will the Duty Officer
break to the paint shop.
Duty Officer
to the paint shop.
You all right, Mr. Tyler?
Tiptop, Eddie. Tiptop.
Wanna thank you
for that liberty pass.
My girl thanks you, too.
You're a good man,
Mr. Tyler.
Heart's in the right place.
Just need to give it
some time.
Yeah, I heard about
what happened to you.
That's one of the advantages
of being seen
and not being seen.
You'd be surprised
some of the shit
we mess stewards hear.
Boy, don't go dropping
my eggs. Now look.
Damn. Excuse me, Mr. Tyler.
Look, all you got to do is
pick them up with both hands,
boy, both hands!
Tyler!
When the hell were you
gonna tell me? I hear
about this from the chief?
What do you want me to say?
He shit-canned me.
Now you're gonna transfer
to another boat.
Excuse me.
Either one of you two. . .
tell me where I can find
the exec of this thing?
Yeah, that's me, mac.
We'll have your truck
unloaded here shortly.
Well, you'll unload it now.
Here's the manifest.
Let's get those crates
below decks.
Who the hell are you?
Marine Major Coonan,
Office of Naval Intelligence.
I'm going to sea
with you boys.
That's my luggage.
You got a problem,
talk to Mr. Hirsch.
Clear!
- Cast off all lines forward!
- Cast off forward !
Take in all lines aft.
Cast off aft!
Rudder amidships.
All ahead one-third.
All ahead one-third!
Bridge hatch shut.
Engine room,
secure the diesels.
Switch the ship propulsion
to the battery.
Engine room,
secure diesels, switch
propulsion to the battery.
- Main induction indicates shut.
- Aye.
Green board, Skipper.
Very well.
Passing the 100-fathom curve.
On course, on time, sir.
Engine room reports
secured diesels, propulsion
switched to battery.
Very well.
All ahead two-thirds.
All ahead two-thirds, aye.
Mr. Emmett, take her down.
Make her depth 150 feet,
10 degree down bubble.
150 feet, 10 degree
down bubble. Aye, sir.
Chief of the watch,
sound the dive alarm.
Pass the word along the 1 MC.
Open the main
ballast tank vents.
Aye, sir, passing the word.
AII ahead
two thirds, sir.
Dive, dive, dive.
Sir, main ballast
tank vents indicate open.
Aye. Both planes dive,
15 degrees.
Both planes dive,
15 degrees. Aye.
All clear!
Decks awash.
Aye, sir.
First time on a submarine?
That's right.
60 feet.
Lower the scope.
Captain, engine room
reports minor flooding from
shaft seals and brine pump.
Bilge is at 18 inches
and rising.
Very well.
How deep
does this thing go?
She'll go
all the way to the bottom
if we don't stop her.
Normally we try
not to get below 150 feet.
Any deeper,
the leaks overwhelm the pumps.
These S-boats are antiques,
older than most of the crew.
100 feet.
Aye.
Excuse me, Mr. Emmett.
Put a pipe patch on it,
lash it with marline.
The yard can fix it
when we get back to port.
Aye, sir.
Relax, gentlemen.
She's old, but she'll hold.
Last night,
at 0300 hours...
a British destroyer
reported depth-charging
and sinking a German U-boat.
However, some time
thereafter. . .
Allied direction-finding
stations triangulated a coded
enemy radio signal. . .
to this position here,
near the CHOP line.
We believe the U-boat
was disabled, not sunk. . .
and is drifting eastward
on a four-knot current.
Now, French resistance
reported a resupply
submarine. . .
sailed from
the Lorient U-boat pens
yesterday afternoon. . .
with engine parts
and mechanics.
And we believe
it's gonna rendezvous
with the disabled U-boat.
Onboard that U-boat is this.
A typewriter?
An Enigma code machine.
It allows the German navy
to communicate with
its submarines in secret.
And our inability
to decipher their messages
is costing us this war.
Mr. Coonan.
All right, this is basically
a Trojan Horse operation.
The S-33 will rendezvous
with the U-boat, posing
as the German resupply sub.
I will lead
a boarding party. . .
dressed in
Kriegsmarine uniforms
to the enemy submarine.
We will take it by force
and secure the Enigma.
Any German survivors
will be transferred
to the S-33. . .
and the U-boat
will be scuttled.
The German resupply
submarine will arrive
at the rendezvous. . .
and will assume that
the U-boat succumbed
to its wounds and sank.
The Germans must never
suspect we have the Enigma.
That is vital.
- So it's a race?
- Yes, effectively.
Who's the boarding party?
Well, since you're the XO,
you, sir.
Mr. Emmett, Mr. Larson,
Mr. Hirsch and nine
of your ship's company.
The captain, of course,
will remain onboard the S-33.
Mr. Coonan, our boys
are submarine sailors,
not combat Marines.
The boys onboard that U-boat
are sailors too.
Your men will be ready,
Lieutenant.
I'll train them myself.
You've come to the right boat.
Ahoy! Friends!
Guten Tag.
We have many wounded !
Take us prisoner, please!
We'll be no trouble.
Give us a hand !
It's the law of the sea,
my friend.
We need water and food !
We just want to get home!
We just need
a bit of a hand.
We have no--
I'm telling you, she
was hotter than Dorothy Lamour
and better built.
Really?
Yeah, I could tell
she was interested.
But she was classy,
you know?
The type of girl that wants
you to take her to a country
club dance or something.
Yeah, like you've ever seen
the inside of a country club.
Hey! Like I'd even want to,
all right?
Anyway, I can see
I'm not getting
anywhere with her. . .
so what I do is,
I use my secret weapon.
I tell her about the S-26.
Does the trick right away.
Man, you don't want
to be talking about that
while we're underway.
Why? What happened
with the S-26?
Yeah, what happened?
You guys don't know?
No.
She was running a test dive
down off Norfolk.
Shaft seal failed.
She sunk to 400 feet.
Know how much water pressure
there is that deep?
Mazzola, you will be
the first one eating
powdered eggs on this cruise.
Keep it up, you hear?
Come in.
This is our position, Captain.
We're still bucking
some pretty heavy seas.
I estimate us to be
about three hours
behind schedule.
I told Mr. Emmett
to run at flank speed
and hold off on a trim dive. . .
until we make up
the lost time.
That's fine, Lieutenant.
You're a first-rate XO,
Andy.
A damn good submariner.
I know the men like you.
I'd give my life
for any one of them, sir.
I know you would.
I'm not questioning
your bravery.
The question is
what about their lives?
You and Mr. Emmett
are good friends.
Went through
the Academy together.
Would you be willing
to sacrifice his life?
Or what about
some of the younger
enlisted men?
I know a lot of those guys
look up to you
like a big brother.
You willing to lay
their lives on the line?
You see? You hesitate.
But as a captain, you can't.
You have to act.
If you don't, you put
the entire crew at risk.
Now that's the job.
It's not a science.
You have to be able
to make hard decisions. . .
based on
imperfect information.
Asking men to carry out
orders that may result
in their deaths.
And if you're wrong,
you suffer the consequences.
If you're not prepared
to make those decisions. . .
without pause,
without reflection. . .
then you've got no business
being a submarine captain.
Tell Mr. Hirsch
I'd like a word with him,
would you?
Aye, sir.
- More soup, Captain?
- Thank you.
Wishing I was going
with you, gentlemen.
I feel the same way
you do, Carson.
Gentlemen, I'd like
to propose a toast.
To the officers and crew
of the S-33. . .
and our distinguished guests,
Mr. Hirsch and Mr. Coonan.
Success, gentlemen !
Success.
Captain Dahlgren, sir?
What is it, Wentz?
Chief says we've picked up
a radar contact at 070.
Very well. Mr. Larson?
Signal lamp
off the starboard bow!
I see it.
Pass the word along.
Submarine sighted
off the starboard bow.
Stand by to man
battle stations.
Aye, sir.
All right, here we go.
One last time.
Lieutenant Tyler's raft gets
from the conning tower aft.
My raft gets the gun crew.
And no one, no one shoots
till I shoot first.
- You read me?
- Yes, sir.
Outstanding. Lock and load.
It'll be all right, son.
Yes, sir.
Captain, I estimate
the German resupply sub has
a 14-knot speed of advance.
My latest plot puts them
at 12 hours away, sir.
Very well, Mr. Larson.
Captain, the boarding party's
ready, sir.
Await your go-ahead.
I put her low
in the water.
I wanna give that U-boat
as little silhouette
as we can.
Sir?
Prepare to disembark
the boarding party.
Aye, Captain.
If this thing
goes south. . .
I will blow that Nazi boat
right out of the water.
Understood, sir.
Very well.
All set, Captain.
Now you listen to me.
You get them their damn trophy
and you get the hell
out of there.
Aye, sir.
The boys are gonna be fine.
I know they will, sir.
Good luck, Andy.
Godspeed, Skipper.
Easy, Mr. Hirsch.
We're almost there.
We're gonna bushwhack them
real good.
All right,
we got 12 men topside,
three on the bridge. . .
four on the foredeck,
five aft.
Now remember, both rafts
need to be tied up
before we move.
Jesus H. Christ.
They got machine guns.
Steady, gentlemen.
Wait for the signal.
Mr. Hirsch.
Hello the boat, you asshole.
Shut up.
Goddamn you, Hirsch,
say something.
Let's board this thing.
Let's board it.
Board it! Get out of the raft.
Conning tower. Move. Move.
Clear the conning tower now!
Watch yourself,
there. Man in the hole.
Another one there!
- Griggs is hit!
- Get him off!
Move, move!
Trigger, round the back. Now!
Griggs! Griggs!
We gotta get inside!
Griggs!
Chief, Tank,
come down now!
Ready?
All right, open it! Fire!
Tyler, let's go!
Inside!
Cover your men ! Go, go!
Don't let them
close it.
Don't let them close it!
Two, three, four,
five. Shut it.
Let's go. Go! Get down ! Go!
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Get off, get off!
Don't move, don't move!
Get back, get back,
get back!
Just drop it! Drop it!
Get them outta here!
You hit?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Stern team, go! Bow team, go!
I'm outta clips, sir.
You go ahead.
Rabbit!
All right, get them
outta here. Get them
outta here. Let's go!
Get down. Down, down,
down, down ! Get down !
All right, who's the captain?
Huh? Who's the captain?
Kapitän?
How about you, ugly?
Are you the captain?
Trigger, if anybody moves. . .
you shoot them right here
in the forehead,
you understand me?
Yes, sir!
All right.
Hirsch, we got it.
Speaking in German]
Get down, down !
Down there!
Down, down !
Rabbit, check the bilge
for a scuttling charge.
Give me your weapon !
- Move, sailor, move!
- Aye, sir!
Goddamn it, stay there.
Hirsch, I think we got
the code books!
Andy, that ink's running.
Dry it.
Okay.
It's water soluble.
Yeah, use the blankets,
use the blankets.
Nothing but pipes and valves,
Mr. Emmett.
Bow compartment secure.
Bunch of Marys.
How you doing?
You're number 10.
There you go.
You having a good night?
Uh-huh.
You ain't gonna be
none too happy
y'all lost this boat.
Lucky number 11, let's go!
It's your first time
looking at a black man,
ain't it?
Get used to it.
Let's go! Get over here!
All right,
hurry it up.
It's gonna be sunup
in an hour.
Fuse is burning, sir.
All right,
she's burning ! Let's go!
Let's get this raft loaded !
Let's move!
Sir, we got
all the prisoners transferred
to the S-33.
Very well.
Hey, Andy.
Make sure
you got everything !
Get in the raft!
Get everything
below decks. Let's go!
Everybody, below decks!
Get down !
Chief, take her down !
Aye, sir!
The scuttling charge!
Let's go, Hirsch !
The Enigma!
Trigger! Grab hold !
Trigger! Attaboy!
I've got it!
Help me! Help me! Oh, no! No!
We gotta get
outta here!
There's still men
in the water.
Let's go!
Chief, there's still men
in the water.
Go!
Andy!
Andy! Go!
Dive!
Take her down !
Tyler.
Dive!
Chief, you find those vents?
Everything's in German !
Rabbit,
get to the torpedo room.
Sir.
Where's the goddamn 1 MC?
Trigger, get on the helm !
Mazzola, take the planes.
Aye, sir.
Wentz,
what about these?
I don't know. I don't know.
There's no label !
Okay, those are
the aft ballast tank vents!
These are the mid-ship vents
and these are
the main induction valves.
Make sure they're shut.
Tank, Tank, I need speed !
Get the screws turning.
The lights are on. . .
so there's got to be
some power left
in those ballasts.
I can't read this!
Rabbit,
find out how many fish
we've got in the tubes. . .
and figure out
how to launch them ! Go!
I can't read this!
Go help Tank, Hirsch.
Go, Hirsch !
Find the Christmas tree.
We've gotta make sure
we don't have any holes
in the boat!
Klar, klar, klar. Wentz,
what the hell is kIar?
KIar means clear.
All compartments secure.
White for green?
White for green.
- No holes in the ship!
- Dive the boat!
Opening ballast vents!
Opening mid-ship valves!
Opening mid-ship vents!
This is forward trim,
aft trim.
These are auxiliaries.
Main motor.
Auxiliary, auxiliary.
This is in meters.
Everything's in meters.
Passing 15 meters.
Recommend shutting main vents!
Make it so! Wentz,
get in the sound room.
See what's out there.
Yes, sir!
Make depth 20 meters.
Depth 20 meters, aye.
Chief, take the dive!
I have the dive.
At 20 meters. Bow planes
at zero. Control your depth
with the stern planes.
Bow planes at zero.
Controlling depth
with the stern planes.
Oh, shit.
All ahead full, sir!
Batteries are flat
and draining fast!
Mr. Tyler, I hear
the S-33 breaking up. Wait.
I hold a submerged U-boat,
010.
Real close.
Less than 1,000 yards.
Goddamn resupply sub.
Trigger, what's our heading?
280, sir.
Aye, right full rudder!
Steady on 010.
Aye, sir! Right full rudder.
Steady on course 010, sir.
Tank, starboard back full.
Rabbit, get back to me.
Starboard back full. Aye, sir.
Watch your depth.
She'll squat.
Rabbit!
We got four fish.
Tubes are flooded.
But I can't open
the muzzle doors
until I equalize.
I can't find the valve!
Wentz, help Rabbit!
Enemy submarine close aboard.
Torpedo in the water.
Torpedo in the water!
All right, belay that.
Wentz, stay where you are!
Hirsch, hotfoot it
to the torpedo room !
Helm, mark your head
every 10 degrees.
Aye, sir.
Now passing 320.
Turn, baby, turn. Turn !
Equalizing valves. Holy shit!
What's what? This is crazy.
I can't equalize the tubes!
What do you need?
Equalizing valves!
Valves?
Gyro?
No.
Drainage.
Some kind of drainage.
No.
Now passing 000.
Swing, you bastard, swing.
Chief, stand by in case
we have to flood forward trim.
Impulse?
No.
Differential.
Pressure differential?
These! Turn them !
This! Turn them !
Which way?
Torpedo missed.
It's in our baffles.
Two more torpedoes
in the water!
Best bearing
to the U-boat, 010.
Aye, Rabbit,
get ready to fire a spread.
Tubes one and two.
Zero gyro. Fire!
Rabbit, fire!
What's going on?
What is that?
Wrong one! Wrong one!
The fish is stuck!
I must've missed
an interlock or something.
Rabbit, get those fish out
before they blow!
Look for "impulse air"
or "firing air."
That was "impulse" there
and there!
One, two, away.
Lining up tubes three
and four.
Three and four, fire!
All fish running hot,
straight and normal.
I think they all missed, sir.
Shit.
U-boat's breaking up!
I hear bulkheads collapsing.
The 33 boat, Mr. Tyler.
Let's take her up
and look for survivors, Chief.
Give me some rise
on the planes!
Rise on the planes, aye.
Deploy main ballast!
Gotcha.
Oh, crap.
Help!
Do you speak English?
English.
What's your rank?
What do you do?
What's your job? Your job.
Job.
You're an electrician. Good.
You can help us
squeeze some more juice
out of them batteries.
Sir, I see the skipper.
Battery's dead.
Whatever juice was left
we used up when we maneuvered.
- What about the diesels?
- Starboard's a wreck.
We need to dry dock
to fix it.
Portside diesel's the good
news. Whoever the Krauts
had wrenching on it. . .
didn't know a piston head
from his sister's titty.
I think I can fix it.
Okay, Tank.
Do what you can.
Yes, sir.
All right. Listen up.
We've decided on a course.
We're heading for England,
Land's End.
It's the closest,
besides occupied France.
Rabbit,
how many torpedoes do we have?
Just one.
It's in the stern tube,
which is busted.
The high pressure
line's bleeding air
from somewhere.
Sir?
Yeah, what is it, Trigger?
Can't we just use the radio?
Fire off a mayday
and wait for a rescue?
That's impossible.
If we transmit, the Germans
will direction-find
our position to a grid. . .
where they're missing
two U-boats.
If they even suspect we have
the Enigma, they will change
their entire coding system.
And that would
completely negate
the purpose of our mission.
Mr. Tyler. . .
if we head for England. . .
we're gonna go
straight through
the western approaches.
He's right. I mean,
that's Jerry's backyard.
Listen, guys.
It's full of U-boats.
And we've got nothing
to defend ourselves with.
Do you think
I got all the answers here?
You think I know how we're
gonna get out of this mess?
I don't. I don't know how.
I say we use the radio.
Nobody asked you.
We use the radio
and take our goddamn chances.
Yeah.
I said, can it.
It's what the captain
would have done--
Captain's dead.
This is crazy.
This whole thing is crazy.
Risking our lives
over a typewriter.
It's not
a typewriter.
The hell it ain't.
It's got buttons
like a typewriter.
Yeah, well, it's not.
Yeah, well, whatever
it is, I say it's crazy we
get ourselves killed over it.
The Navy says
it's important,
it's important.
The Navy says
it's more important
than you, him, me, fine.
We're gonna die trying.
And that ain't crazy.
That's our job.
Well, what I don't
seem to understand, Chief. . .
is how come
you're not in charge?
Scuttlebutt is Dahlgren was
kicking Tyler out of the Navy
anyway, and everybody--
You stow that shit
right now, sailor.
Lieutenant Tyler is
your commanding officer. . .
and you will respect
that man as such.
Do you understand?
Yes, Chief.
Look at them sons of bitches.
You know my pop
was a fisherman?
He had this old 60-footer
he'd run all over the Gulf.
Noisy two-stroke diesel.
Rotten to the gunnels,
that thing.
I could scrub that deck
three times a day,
and it still stunk like fish.
And I swore I'd never
skipper a boat like that,
Chief.
I saw myself. . .
standing on the bridge
of a battleship.
A real sea captain.
Mr. Tyler,
permission to speak freely?
Of course, Chief.
This is the Navy. . .
where a commanding officer
is a mighty
and terrible thing.
A man to be feared
and respected.
All knowing, all powerful.
Don't you dare say
what you said to the boys back
there again, "I don't know."
Those three words
will kill a crew,
dead as a depth charge.
You're the skipper now.
And the skipper
always knows what to do,
whether he does or not.
Aircraft
off the port bow!
Shit!
Real sorry, sir.
It dropped right out
of the clouds.
Rabbit, Trigger,
stand by the flak gun.
Sir.
It's German. Looks like
long-range reconnaissance.
What the hell's
it doing way out here?
Jesus, here it comes.
All right. Sit tight.
As far as he knows, we're all
playing on the same team.
Everybody wave.
Wave?
Sir, we're sitting ducks.
If we shoot first, we can
blow them out of the sky.
We shoot and miss,
he's gonna radio us in.
That plane's gonna be the
least of our problems.
This is crazy.
You're gonna get us killed.
He's coming around.
He's coming around !
He's attacking !
For Christ's sake, Rabbit,
do something !
Mazzola, shut up.
Rabbit, ignore him.
Do something !
He's gonna strafe us, Rabbit!
He's coming right at us!
It's lined up! Do something !
Acknowledge me, Seaman Parker.
What are you
waiting for?
Yeah, Rabbit! Shoot him !
Seamen Parker,
I'm ordering you !
Do not fire that weapon !
Get your finger off
that trigger!
Pull the trigger!
We're gonna die!
Do it! Do it!
Come on ! Goddamn it,
can't you see him?
What the hell
are you doing, huh?
This is not
a goddamn democracy!
Mr. Tyler,
I see a mast on the horizon !
Shit!
That's a Nazi destroyer.
That plane
must have been running
a recon screen for it.
Clear the bridge!
Chief, secure the diesel
and dive the ship!
Dive the ship!
Aye, sir!
We don't have
a green board, sir.
What's wrong?
The engine room's not ready.
No power
on the starboard engine.
Vents won't open.
We lost hydraulics.
Tank, secure the diesel
and rig the engine room
for dive!
Tank, acknowledge!
Goddamn it! Mazzola, go see
what the hell's going on
back there.
Drop it, you Nazi
son of a bitch ! Drop it!
Goddamn it.
I'm real sorry,
Mr. Tyler.
Took me right off my feet.
Listen to me.
You've got to
secure the diesel.
And find out
why the vent valves
won't open. Now!
Yes, sir.
Goddamn it!
Eddie, get this son of a bitch
out of here. Chain him up
to the bunks.
Make sure his hands
and feet are secure.
Put him into submission !
Lieutenant, we have
a big problem!
Take care of it, Eddie.
Oh, shit.
Tell Tank to finish
those repairs. The destroyer
is sending a launch.
He needs five minutes,
Mr. Tyler!
We don't have
five minutes, Chief.
Lieutenant, the deck cannon.
If we fire a shell
below the water line. . . .
It wouldn't do
a goddamn thing. No, that tub
could take a hundred shells.
What we need
is a working torpedo,
which we do not have.
Trigger, stand by
on the flak gun, and when
I give you the word. . .
turn that launch
into driftwood. All right?
Yes, sir.
Gonna find out who we are
in about 60 seconds.
Trigger,
ready on that weapon?
Chief, tell Tank
he has one minute. . .
and get Wentz and Rabbit
up here with the machine gun.
Hirsch, what'll happen
when they find out
we're not German?
After they shoot us as spies,
they'll radio
into headquarters.
They'll tell them
the Enigma's been
compromised.
What if we take out
their radio, before they can
notify anyone about us?
How?
With that deck gun.
It's gonna be
one hell of a shot,
but we can do it.
Then we dive like hell,
and we get under them quick.
We lure them a little bit
closer to the continent,
in range of Allied air cover.
Then we call in
an air strike.
Mr. Tyler.
Yeah, we call in
an air strike.
Son of a bitch cut off
pressure to the hydraulics.
We need to find
the stop valve.
Damn !
See that structure
topside just aft
of the flying bridge. . .
with the big antenna
sticking out of it?
Yes, sir.
That's the radio shack.
You and Wentz
get on the deck gun.
On my command, I want you
to put a shell right through
the goddamn porthole.
Get to it, gentlemen.
Get to it.
Yes, sir.
Tell them to go away,
Mr. Hirsch.
Talk to me, Rabbit!
Deck gun manned
and ready in all respects,
sir.
Fire.
Clear the deck.
Dive! Dive! Dive!
Come on.
Why aren't we diving?
Repairs aren't complete, sir.
- Eddie, man the planes.
- Aye, sir!
Tank, all ahead full.
Aye, sir! Manning the planes!
All ahead full, aye!
Nice shot, Rabbit.
That radio's history.
We're heading
right towards them.
That's right.
Her deck guns can't get to us,
if we're in close enough.
Let's hope we can dive
and clear her keel.
That's it.
Hydraulics restored.
Thank you, Tank.
That did it.
We're going under.
Passing five meters.
Passing 10 meters.
15 meters.
20 meters.
Trigger,
left full rudder.
Tank, all ahead two-thirds.
Contact maneuvering.
Heavy cavitation.
Splashes.
Step away from that bulkhead,
Mr. Hirsch.
The shock wave from
one of these explosions
can snap your spine.
Chief. . .
you ever been depth charged?
Once. . .
off Murmansk. . .
back in World War I.
One charge came so close,
it rattled four teeth out
of the skipper's head.
Wasn't even close.
Control, the starboard
e-motor's seized up.
The German must have
sabotaged it.
Goddamn it.
There's no way we make it
to Allied air cover
creeping along on one shaft.
Eddie, help Chief.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Chief, I got that.
Tank, you alive back there?
Yes, sir.
Good.
Port ahead two-thirds.
Aye, sir.
Tank. . .
can you fix the stern tube?
I don't know, Mr. Tyler.
I don't want
an "I don't know."
Can you fix
the torpedo tube? Yes or no?
Yes, sir. I think I can.
Thank you, Tank.
Chief. . .
make depth 160 meters.
That's more than 500 feet.
Take us down, Chief.
Aye, sir.
160 meters.
20 degrees dive,
both planes.
aye, sir.
20 degrees dive, aye, sir.
Mr. Tyler, sir. . .
you planning on
going up against
a destroyer with. . .
only one fish in the tube
and a busted motor?
Yes, I am, Eddie.
How wise is that, Lieutenant?
Not very.
But have a look. Chief.
There is no way
a two-knot submarine,
can get in firing position. . .
against a 30-knot destroyer,
unless we go deep.
At 160 meters. . .
we can shoot out
a bunch of junk
from the forward tubes.
It will resurface
and create a debris field.
Now the destroyer's gonna go
to the center
of that debris field. . .
shut off its engines
to make it real nice
and quiet. . .
and do an acoustic search,
to make sure we're dead.
But we're not.
See, we're here. . .
on our way
up to periscope depth.
All right,
principle of ascent velocity.
We let our positive buoyancy
pull us up,
and away from the destroyer.
And when we surface,
we'll be showing it
our ass at 700 yards.
That is a perfect setup
for a stern shot
on a stationary target.
Boom.
It don't get
much prettier than that.
All right, Mr. Tyler.
All right.
Passing 130 meters.
Very well.
Rabbit, I need you
to load Mazzola's body
into tube three. . .
and put an escape jacket
onto him
to make sure he floats.
Gonna shoot him out
like garbage?
His body is gonna save
our lives.
I'll say a few words
for him.
Hirsch, go with Rabbit.
Eddie, can you man
both planes?
Yes, sir.
Mr. Tyler.
Yeah.
If you can't take out
that destroyer. . .
the danger is not that
some of us may die. . .
but that some of us
may live.
These men have seen
and heard things. . .
that must not be revealed
to the enemy.
Our secrets. . .
such as our
radar capabilities. . .
and our understanding
of German encryption.
If we fall into German hands
alive, we will be tortured
without mercy.
Either you succeed
in sinking that ship. . .
or you must see to it
that none of us survive. . .
to be captured.
We commend his soul
to God. . .
and commit his body
to the deep.
Mr. Tyler,
contact is zigging.
Splashes.
Contact getting closer.
More splashes.
Tank. . .
line out to pump engine
room bilge to sea.
Yes, sir.
Rabbit. . .
fire the tubes.
Bye, Mazzola.
They setting them charges
too shallow.
Secure that air valve.
Chief. . .
what's our depth?
160 meters.
Zero the planes.
Splashes!
They're too close together!
I can't count them.
Chief. . .
take us to 200 meters.
We're gonna get under
these damn things.
Chief. . .
take us to 200 meters.
Aye, sir.
Making my depth 200 meters.
10 degrees dive, both planes.
10 degrees dive,
both planes.
10 degrees dive. Aye.
170 meters.
Tank. . .
what's the status
on the stern torpedo tube?
There's a couple things wrong.
I can operate the muzzle door
now. . .
but I'm still working
on the impulse air.
180 meters.
Mr. Tyler,
depth gauge back here
says 180 meters.
Thanks, Tank. I know.
Keep working.
190 meters.
200 meters.
Zero the planes.
Zero the planes, aye.
Mary, mother of God.
Those Krauts sure know
how to build a boat.
Chief, take us up!
Blowing negative!
Planes full rise!
Clockwise, Hirsch ! Clockwise!
- All right!
- Hurry up!
Go! Go!
Move it, move it!
Chief, are you seeing this?
Needle's off the scale.
We have to blow
main ballast tanks.
Do it, Chief!
She's still going down !
Ballast tanks are bone dry.
I'm gonna try the trim tanks.
Come on, come on !
She's going up.
Mr. Tyler, we're coming up.
But I've lost control
over the ballast tanks.
I can't stop our ascent.
Where are we
with the stern torpedo?
Piping's damaged.
There's a break in the air
line, so there's no pressure
to launch the torpedo.
I tried to bypass the leak,
but it's way back
in the bilge underwater.
There's no way
to reach it. I can't fit.
Think somebody else
could do it?
I don't know.
Maybe somebody smaller.
That's Rabbit or Trigger.
Coming up on 200 meters.
You gotta pick one.
Trigger.
Trigger. . .
lay aft with Tank.
Move it, son.
You got a job to do.
See here,
we got no air pressure
to fire the torpedo.
One of these pipes is busted
and it's leaking air.
How am I gonna find it?
You'll see bubbles
coming out.
A lot of them.
Find the isolation valve
aft of the leak,
and crank it down.
Got it?
Yeah.
I rigged this hose
so you can breathe through it.
Now listen to me.
As soon as you finish,
you get out of there.
Okay?
Yeah.
I can hear her.
Making slow turns.
She just stopped her screws.
I think they see the debris.
I think they're buying it.
180 meters.
Chief, can you slow
our ascent some?
We are not ready.
Can't, sir.
We got a one-way ticket
topside.
If we surface without
a torpedo to fire, we're dead.
There's two air leaks.
I got one,
but the other one's
way in the back.
I need some more
slack on the hose
to get to it.
That's all there is.
Shit.
150 meters.
I hear Morse code.
What the hell is it?
Are they signaling us?
What's it saying, Wentz?
"I am U-571. Destroy me."
Coming up on 90 meters.
Sir, she's started
her engines again.
No go, Mr. Tyler.
He can't reach.
Trigger. . .
in one minute
we're gonna hit the surface.
Do you understand me?
Now you've got to
go back in there and try.
I wouldn't ask you
if our lives
didn't depend on it.
Sorry, sir. I can't reach it.
No, no, Trigger.
Now listen to me.
You can reach it,
and you will.
Now you are gonna close
that valve.
I can't!
God damn it,
you're the only chance
we've got.
Now you're gonna
go back down in that bilge. . .
and you're gonna
do your job, sailor.
Report to me the instant
that torpedo's ready to fire.
Yes, sir.
30 meters.
- Talk to me, Wentz.
- Destroyer is underway.
Steady bearing.
They're closing our position.
Shit! Come on, Trigger!
20 meters.
Hold on. We're gonna surface.
Raising scope.
Got her.
She's heading right for us.
elm, come right 10 degrees.
Helm, come right
10 degrees. Aye, sir!
Watch your bow planes.
Aye, sir.
Watching my bow planes.
Tank, start the diesel.
All ahead full.
Port diesel ahead full.
Shit, they've got us
bracketed.
Incoming.
We're hit!
Wentz, get in here.
Eddie,
secure that hatch.
Tube still not ready.
Request permission
to abandon ship.
Not yet, Chief.
Control, answer.
Torpedo now ready
in all respects.
Hold us right there, Rabbit.
Hold us steady right here.
Steady on bearing
80 degrees, sir.
Fire.
Tank, fire right now
or we die!
Come on.
Okay, come on.
That blew them right in half.
Hell, Mr. Tyler,
if you ever need a chief. . .
I'd go to sea
with you anytime.
Thank you, Chief.
Tank, you okay?
Trigger drowned.
That kid didn't give up,
did he?
Neither did you, Mr. Tyler.
We can't keep her afloat
much longer, sir.
Let's abandon ship.
Mr. Tyler. Sir.