SPRING 1942
Hitler's U-Boats sink a thousand
Allied ships in the North Atlantic
threatening the supply
of England by America
Unable to decipher
U-Boot radio codes
the Allies blindly fight
the German offensive
Target speed, 8
Starboard forward 60
Target established
Established depth
Range 500 meters
10, 0, 9, 3
Speed ​​35 knots
Prepare tubes 1 and 4
Tubes 1 and 4 ready
Hunt!
Hunted torpedoes
Impact
Bravo !
Well aimed
There you are, Gentlemen!
We had them!
Fast propellers!
Cap 180
Destroyer !
Dive 90 meters
Before any
Crew up front!
Close torpedo launcher
20 bar
Check the seal
200 degrees, 210
45 m. We dive fast, Commander
Where we are ?
Stabilized at 220
Contact sonar tribord
Stop port engine
Port engine stopped
Port engine, slow aft
Grenades !
Hang on!
The roast beef shits on us
Seal up!
We're 120m away, Commander
Hunt the ballasts! Area !
Look out for the kiosk!
Machine room, answer!
Hans! A damage report!
They're all dead, Commander
The Chief Engineer, the others
the big one, all of them.
They are all dead
Port exhaust destroyed
Wet port diesel
Flooded clutch
- Starboard diesel ...
- I know
- The batteries ?
- damaged
300 amps at the bow, 200 at the stern
Damn!
Barely enough to dive
and maneuver
Thanks, Hans
Say save electricity
Radio !
Contact BDU
Position
85-32
HS diesel engines
Electric propulsion only
Send help
Ministry of the Navy
Submarine Squadron
Here it is !
Andy! Where have you been ?
Come and let me introduce you to Joanie
Joanie, Andy Tyler, my best friend.
We did Annapolis together
Nice to meet you
Here, a Larson cigar.
For our future Pasha
Lieutenant! Will you come to
drink with the guys?
Heard, Griggs
- Can I introduce you to my Mother?
- Of course
He's the one I told you about
Louise. Mrs. Dahlgren. commanding officer
You are alone ?
It doesn't look like you
It is because I was warned very
late, Madam
Can I say a word to you,
Commander?
Certainly
You apologize? I will be back
I don't have my Command
I know
Sorry, Commander,
but I can only see one explanation
That you refused your deposit
That's right
You are not ready
What do you mean, not ready?
I did my best on the S-33
I am the highest rated
of all the Officers in Second
You are not ready
to assume a Command
I've made my decision.
And that's all
Are you okay, Lieutenant?
You are having fun ?
And how, Chief
And you ?
I can't wait to get on board.
I miss the sea air
He torpedoed me, Chief
Nine months aboard the S-33
to do the best job possible
Do everything twice rather than once
to be sure
not to miss anything
Your turn will come, Lieutenant.
There are other Commandments
Did you know ?
You didn't tell me anything
It wasn't for me to do it
The Mess is closed. Withdraw
Explain yourself, sergeant
- Are you the responsible officer?
- The Second of S-33
These men have a
48-hour leave
Not anymore, Lieutenant
Team 3
To the report before the relief
Team 3,
to the report of the Principal Master
What are they doing to my boat?
Looks like a Nazi Submarine
Another coup from the Navy
Detachment C, to security
I didn't have 5 minutes
to consummate my marriage
- What is happening ?
- I don't know
Cover yourself
- Gather the Crew
- Yes, Commander
Gathering! In a row !
Execution!
We hurry!
Crew present, Captain
Perfect
Repos !
Sorry for your permission.
Change of program
We have two hours
to board and set sail
Mr. Larson, let your torpedo boats
load the tubes
Mr. Emmett,
heat up the diesels
Mr. Tyler, we have food
and equipment to embark
Gentlemen, it's up to us!
That's it
Take care of yourself !
Break ranks!
Execution!
You have 6 seconds
to get dressed!
- Isn't that a workout?
- I'll take my mother home tomorrow
But we had permission.
What's going on?
I dunno
I will inquire
At work
We obviously do
n't sail for the Carabs, Commander
We are going on a special operation
You will receive your instructions
after fitting
At your service !
Listen, Andy
I rely on you 100%
despite our dispute
It's heard ?
Well
Discreetly drive
the Wentz radio to the hardware
Are you alright, son?
Alright, Admiral
- What brings you ?
- Him. It's Lieutenant Hirsch
He embarks with you
For this operation, you no
longer depend on us, but on him
He's the boss.
He decides everything
This is the Minister's point of view
Good
It's him ?
I was told
that your family
is from Koblenz
A real family
of Rhenish peasants
Do you understand me, Herr Wentz?
Do you speak German fluently?
Can you read and write it?
Or are you an illiterate redneck
in the German name?
I am a redneck
but I can read and write
and I speak well
I studied German
at university before committing
to the fight against fascism
Thanks, Wentz
It will be fine
You can dispose
Prepare the departure,
Lieutenant
Please
don't say i'm
half german
On me haïrait
Count on me
You are fine ?
Absolutely fine, Eddie
Thank you for the permission
My girlfriend too
You are a good guy
You have a good heart
Let time take its course
Yes i am aware
This is the advantage
of going unnoticed
We hear everything, us
Watch out for my eggs!
Take the boxes with both hands
Had to tell me,
I learn it from the Chef
I have nothing to say. He fucked me up
Are you going to be transferred?
Excuse me. Where is the Second?
It's me.
We will unload your truck
Right now
Here is the list. Embark that
Who are you ?
Major Coonan, Intelligence.
I embark with you
This is my luggage.
Don't you like it? See Hirsch
Drop the point!
Drop the rear!
Rudder at zero, forward slow
Kiosk closed
Engine room,
switch to electric propulsion
Closed diesels
Green indicator
180 m deep, compliant
Electric propulsion
Before two thirds
Dive 150 feet.
Dive bar at 10
Give the dive alert.
Open the ballasts
Order transmitted, Commander
Diving!
The ballasts are open
Dive bars 15
Submerged bridge
It's the first time ?
Absolutely
60 feet
Retract the periscope
Small leak on shaft
and fresh water pump
18 inches of water in the bilge
How far does it go?
Basically, if we let it happen
Normally, we stop at 150 feet.
Otherwise the pumps provide more
This tub is older
than the Crew
100 feet
Seal and place lusin
We will repair at the port
Relax.
He's old, but he's holding up
Yesterday at 3 a.m.
an English Destroyer sank
a U-Boot
but soon after,
the allied stations
have spotted a radio signal
here near the dividing line
U-Boot must be disabled,
not sunk
and drift east at 4 knots
The Resistance says
a Supply Submarine
left Lorient yesterday
with parts and Mechanics
We think
that he will join the U-Boot
On board the U-Boot, there is this
- A typewriter ?
- An ENIGMA encryption machine
With her, the Germans
communicate in secret
Unable to decipher their
messages, we will lose the war
It's the trojan's blow
The S-33 will replace the
German supply submarine
At the head of a commando disguised
as German sailors
I will take
over the U-Boot and the ENIGMA
After transferring the survivors,
we will scuttle the U-Boot
The Supply Submarine
will believe that the U-Boot ended
up sinking
The enemy must not suspect
a thing
It is vital
- Is it a race?
- Indeed
- Who will the commando understand?
- You, as Second
Emmett, Larson
Hirsch and 9 men
The Commander will remain aboard
the S-33
Our men are Submarines,
not Marines
Your men will be ready,
I will train them
We will be up to the task
Okay, we try
Do you call yourself a mechanic?
I was an apprentice with my uncle,
I repaired motorcycles
I do what I can
Here we are!
Commander, on the bridge!
I need a Mechanic
Guten Tag!
We have a lot of injuries
Take us prisoner
What do they want?
That we collect them
Impossible. Open fire
What?
No castaways on board.
Order of FÜHRER
And if we leave them
they risk
giving our position
Execution!
More exciting than Dorothy Lamour
No kidding ?
And I interested her,
but she had class
The kind we take
to a select club
You never set foot there
And i don't miss it
In any case
I saw that I was getting
nowhere with her
and I pulled out my secret weapon
I mentioned the S-26. It worked
Don't talk about it now
What is the story of the S-26?
Don't you know?
A test dive
off Norfolk
A waterway
He sank at 400 feet
Can you imagine the pressure?
Mazzola !
I reserve the powdered eggs for you
Come in
This is our position
The sea is rough,
we are 3 hours late
I told Emmett to force
the speed to catch up
It's perfect
You are an excellent Second
A really good Submariner
Men like you
I would give my life for them
I know.
I don't doubt your bravery
The question is their own life
You and Emmett are friends
You did Annapolis together
Would you be ready to sacrifice
his life?
And the youngest sailors?
They see you
as a big brother
Would you risk their lives?
You see, you hesitate
The Commander can't hesitate
He must act
Otherwise, he puts the whole crew
in danger.
It's our job.
It's not a science
Knowing how to make
difficult decisions while being poorly informed
Giving orders
that may result in death
And, in case of error,
bear the consequences
If we're not ready
to make these decisions
without hesitation, without thinking
you cannot order
a Sub
Tell Hirsch
I want to talk to him
Shall I tighten you up, Commander?
I would like to go with you
It's my feeling too
Gentlemen, a toast
To the Officers and Crew
of the S-33
And to our hosts,
MM Hirsch and Coonan
To our success, Gentlemen
- Commanding officer ?
- What is it ?
The Chief says we have
radar contact at 70
Forward starboard signal!
I see him
Spread the word
Submarine in sight.
At battle stations
Alright, one last time
Tyler takes over the booth
I, machine gunners
Nobody shoots before me
Including ?
Perfect. Arm
Everything will be alright
The supply U-Boot spins 14 knots
So it's 12 hours from here
The commando awaits your signal
I try to show
as little as possible to the U-Boot
Prepare to land the commando
If it fails I'll sink these Nazis
It's understood
Perfect
Ready!
Listen to me carefully
Capture their toy
and come back immediately
The sailors will be perfect
I know, Commander
Good luck
Good winds, Commander
Our comrades bring eggs
bananas
and even our mail!
Calm down, Hirsch
We are almost there
We will pay for them
They are 12.3
on the kiosk
4 at the bow, 5 at the stern
We must moor the rafts
before acting
Whore !
They have machine guns
Calm down
Wait for the signal
You're in luck !
We have work for you
- Greet them!
- Shut up
Damn say something
Who are the mechanics?
We are all mechanical aces
It will be fixed at dawn
Who wants this filth?
A bunch of dirty letters
and porn pictures?
It stinks of French perfume!
A real bag of shit!
I'm crazy about it!
welcome aboard
Are you from Wiesbaden?
Go up!
Push them back
Diving!
Booth ! Quickly !
Clean the kiosk!
Another !
Griggs is hit!
Trigger, behind!
You have to enter!
Get off!
Quick, open! Fire!
Tyler, forward!
Come in!
Cover your men!
Prevent them from closing!
Open the ballasts
Let's drown this vermin!
Get your ass off!
Faster ! Diving!
Close !
Get off!
Do not move !
Back off!
Drop it off !
Fire!
Take them!
- It's okay ?
- Yes, Lieutenant
Stern team! Leading team!
I have no more charger
Take them out
On your knees!
Who is the Commander?
Are you the awful one?
At the first gesture, shoot! Including ?
On l'a
Don't shoot!
On your knees!
See if they've trapped the hold
Your weapon!
Do not move !
On a les codes !
Ink is flowing, dry them
It is soluble
With blankets
There are only pipes
We hold the bow
Bunch of wimps
Is it gauzy?
You're number 10
Is the evening good?
The FÜHRER will not be happy
The 11th brings good luck
You've never seen black, eh?
You will get used to
Go! This way !
Only an hour before dawn!
The wick burns
Load the raft!
Let's hurry!
The prisoners
are on board the S-33
Load everything on the raft
Let's go!
Come in everyone! We are being attacked!
Chief ! In diving!
- Lives !
- THE ENIGMA!
Get off everyone!
Catch!
Help !
You have to get out
- There are more
- Let's go
Andy !
Go for it !
In diving!
- Can you find them?
- Everything is in German
Rabbit, torpedo launcher
Where's the intercom?
Trigger, at the helm
- And that ?
- I dunno. There is nothing written
Rear ballasts
Diesel air intake
- Shut them up
- Give me speed
There must be
juice in the batteries
I understand nothing !
Count the torpedoes
and see how to launch them
- I don't understand anything
- Go help him
The indicators
Let everything be closed
What is it, klar?
It means "clear".
Everything is closed
White, is it green?
Everything is closed.
Make us dive
Open the ballasts!
Opening of ballasts
Front compensator. Back.
And that, the auxiliaries
Main motor.
Auxiliary
Everything is in meters
Depth 15 m
Closing of ballasts?
Close
Wentz, go to the hydrophone
Stabilize at 20 m
Take control
I have them
Twenty meters
Front dive bar at zero
Shit !
The batteries are dead,
Commander
They empty
I hear the S-33 breaking
Wait
I have a diving U-Boot at 10
Very close. Less than half a mile
- The mothership! Our course?
- 280
All starboard. Stabilize on 10
Full aft port
- Rabbit, answer
- Full aft port
Watch your depth
Rabbit !
We have 4. The tubes must be prepared
- But I can't find the valve
- Go help him
The enemy is approaching! A torpedo!
Stay where you are
Hirsch, go to the torpedoes
- Announce the course every 10
- 320
Vire, small
Holy shit, this is crazy!
I can not fill!
- What are you looking for ?
- Filling !
Gyro ?
Drain?
Zero degrees!
You're going to turn, you bastard!
We might have to open
the compensator before
Propulsion ?
- Pressure differential?
- That's it ! Turn!
What meaning ?
Unlike needles
of a watch
The torpedo missed us
2 new torpedoes!
Better course towards U-Boot
10 degrees
Prepare to shoot
Tubes 1 and 2.
Gyroscope at zero. Fire!
Fire!
What's going on ?
What is that ?
They are stuck!
There is a security
Hunt them before they fart!
- Look for something like "propulsion"
- It was there! And there!
1 and 2 hunted. I prepare 3 and 4
3 and 4, fire!
The 4 eels are spinning
They missed us
Holy shit!
U-Boot jumped
I hear the partitions crack
The S-33!
Let's surface for the survivors
Orient the dive bars.
Drive out ballasts
Shit
You speak English ?
Your rank?
What are you doing ?
Specialty?
Electrician? Good
You will help us with the batteries
I see the Pasha!
The batteries are dead
We emptied them while maneuvering
The diesels?
The starboard engine
can only be repaired in dry dock
The port engine is better
The Boches knew nothing about it
I believe I can fix
Do for the best
Okay listen to me
We decided on a route
Focus on England
It is the closest
outside of France
- How many torpedoes do we have?
- One in the rear tube
But the compressed air leaks
What, Trigger?
Why not the radio?
We send an SOS and we wait
It's impossible
The Germans will locate us
where they lost 2 U-Boats
If they suspect that we have ENIGMA,
they will change numbers
It would be the failure of our mission
Heading for England
means heading west
He is right
- The Boches are at home
- Listen to me
- It's crawling with U-Boot!
- And we are disarmed
Do you think I have the answer
to everything?
That I know how to get out of it?
But no
I do not know
- I'm for the radio
- We didn't ring you
- Take the risk
- I said shut up
- The Commander ...
- He's dead!
That's crazy
All this is crazy
Risking your life
for a typewriter
This is not a
Yes, she has keys
- It's not
- Still, it's crazy
It's the Navy that decides
If the Navy says it matters more
than us, we'll die
It's not crazy, it's our job
It would be up to you
to order us, Chef
Seems Dahlgren was going to
fire Tyler from the Navy
Stop your bullshit, sailor!
Lieutenant Tyler is your Officer,
you respect him
It's understood ?
Look at these bastards
My father was a fisherman
Boss of a small trawler
He was doing the whole Gulf,
with a two-stroke diesel
rotten to the gunwale
No matter how much I washed the deck,
it still stank of fish
I swore I would never
order one like this
I saw myself
on the bridge of a battleship
A true Commander
Can I speak frankly?
Of course
In the Navy
the Commander
is a terrible power
a feared and respected man
omniscient and almighty
Don't ever tell them
"I don't know" again
These words kill a Crew
worse than a grenade
You are the Pasha. The Pasha
always knows what to do
Plane to port before!
Sorry, he
suddenly burst out of the clouds
Rabbit, Trigger, the machine gun!
German. Looks like
a reconnaissance device
What is he doing so far away?
He's coming!
Do not move.
For him, we are on the same team
Let him know
You have to shoot first to get it
If we miss it, it will signal us
It will be much worse
You're going to get us killed!
He returns !
He attacks. Do something
- Shut up
- Do something
He's going to strafe us!
- Sailor Parker!
- What are you waiting for?
- Drawn !
- I order you not to shoot!
- Let go of the trigger!
- Drawn !
- We're going to die!
- Let go of the trigger!
Where do you think you are?
The Navy is not a democracy!
I see a mast on the horizon!
Shit. A Nazi Destroyer
Zinc was in gratitude
for him
Evacuate the bridge
- Prepare to dive
- At your command!
The indicator is not green.
It's the machines
Ballasts respond more
Tank, get ready to dive!
Answer!
Go see what's going on
Drop it, Nazi bastard
I apologize
He knocked me out
Listen
Find out why ballasts
are more responsive!
Chain me the hands
and feet of that bastard
Immobilize it
Lieutenant !
Do it, Eddie
Tell Tank to fix it fast
- They send a star
- It takes 5 minutes
We don't have them
The cannon can hit it
below the waterline
It would be useless
It would take a hundred
We would need a torpedo
Trigger, with the machine gun.
On my signal, destroy the speedboat
They will unmask us
Trigger, get ready
Tank has a minute.
Send Wentz and Rabbit with a PM
What will they do when they know?
After shooting us down
they will warn HQ
about ENIGMA
Let's destroy their radio
- Before they have time
- How?
At the cannon
Difficult, but doable
Then we dive quickly
We train them within range
of our aerial cover
We ask for a strike
That's it
He cut the controls
We must find the stop
Do you see the large antenna
behind the catwalk?
It's the radio
To the cannon, to my command
you put me a shell in this porthole
It's your turn
Shall we send you a rope?
Right now
This is weird
It's a trap
Send them back
Hands up
Tackle!
Faster !
- Rabbit!
- Ready to fire!
Fire!
Evacuate the bridge!
Quickly ! They shoot us
Who ?
The U-Boot.
They destroyed our radio
Immersion !
- Why don't we dive?
- They are still repairing
At the dive bars
Forward all
Hit to the goal. The radio is destroyed
- We go on them
- Exactly
To be safe from their guns
It will remain to pass under the keel
That's it
- Order repaired
- Done . We dive
5 meters
10 meters
15 meters
20 meters
Port side all
Before 2 thirds
He maneuvers
Fast propellers
Grenadage
Close intervals
Get ready to grenade
Adjust depth 25
Get away from the wall
The shock wave
can break your neck
Have you ever been pomegranated?
Once
Off Murmansk,
during the other war
One passed so close
that the Pasha lost four teeth
It was far
Starboard electric motor stopped
The German will have sabotaged it
We won't do it
on a single propeller
Help the Chef
Chief, here I am
Tank
still alive ?
Good
Front port engine 2l3
Can you fix the tube?
I dunno
This is not an answer
Can you fix the tube,
yes or no?
Yes, Commander
Let's go down to 160 meters
It's over 500 feet
Got to get down, Chief
160 meters
Dive bars 20
Commandant ?
You plan to attack
a Destroyer with
one torpedo, one engine?
Exactly
Is this very wise?
Not very
But come see
No way to shoot
a Destroyer spinning 30 knots
unless you sink
At 160 m, we will chase debris
through the front tubes
They will surface
The Destroyer will gain the area,
stop the machines
to ensure the sonar
of our destruction
Except that...
we will be here
ascent to
periscope depth
Archimedes principle
Our buoyancy goes up
as we move away from the Destroyer
We'll surface half a mile away
with our backs to it
Perfect position for
rear firing on a fixed target
We can't dream better
Alright, Mr. Tyler
130 meters
Load Mazzola into tube 3
with a life jacket
so that he goes up
How do we throw garbage?
His corpse will save our lives
I will say a prayer for him
Hirsch, accompany Rabbit
Eddie, will you hold the bars?
If you fail
the danger is not
that we would die
but that we survive
These men know things that
the enemy must not know
at any cost
Secrets
like our radar capabilities
and our knowledge
of their number
If they take us alive
we'll be tortured
Or you manage to sink
the Destroyer
or you will
ensure that none of us survive
to be captured
We commend his soul to God
and his body to the abyss
Port all!
It zigzags
Grenadage
He gets closer
More pomegranates
Water must be removed
from the bilges of the machines
Hunt the tubes
They settle them too short
Block that!
Depth?
160 meters
Zero bars
Grenadage!
Too close together
I can't count them
Take us down to 200 m
That we are under this filth
I go down to 200 m
Dive bars at 10
170 meters
What is the condition of the rear tube?
Two things wrong
The panels work
but I'm working on the propulsion
180 meters
I have 180 meters, here
Thanks, I know
Keep working
190 meters
200 meters
Zero bars
Holy Mary Mother of God
These Boches know how to build
a boat
On remonte !
In the other direction, Hirsch!
Rabbit! Help me !
Chief ! look
We're over the counter!
You have to hunt ballasts
Do it, Chef!
It always goes down
The ballasts are empty!
I try the compensators
On remonte
We go up
But I have more control.
I can't stop our ascent
Where is the tube?
The pipes are damaged
I have no pressure to hunt
The leak is at the bottom of the hold,
under water
I can't reach it.
I don't pass
- Who can do it?
- I dunno
Someone smaller
Rabbit ou Trigger
We go back 200 meters
Must choose
Join Tank
Quick, son
You have a job
You see ? There is no pressure
One of the pipes is leaking
- How do I find him?
- Thanks to the bubbles
Close the valve
behind the leak
Pigeon?
I made you a respirator
Listen carefully. As soon as you finish, you come out
I hear it
It turns slowly
The propellers stop
They must have seen the debris
They believe in it
180 meters
Can you slow us down?
We are not ready
No, Commander
We only have one way
If we surface without a torpedo,
we're dead
There are two leaks.
The second is far away
Give me some pipe
- There's no more
- Shit
150 meters
You morse!
What is that ?
Are they talking to us?
What does it say ?
"I am U-571. Destroy me"
90 meters
The propellers take off again
Failed, Mr. Tyler. It is too far
In a minute we surface,
you know?
You have to go back in there
to try
Our lives depend on it
I don't get that far
Listen to me
You can and you will
You will close this valve
This is our only chance
You will return to the hold
and do your job, sailor
Call me when the torpedo
is ready
30 meters
- Wentz?
- The Destroyer moves
He stays the course
Right on us
20 meters
We are going to surface
I take out the periscope
I see him
He comes right at us
To starboard 10
Watch the bars
Diesel in full swing
Diesel port before any
They crisscross us!
Shells!
We are touched!
- Wentz, come here!
- Eddie, close the hatch
Not ready yet
Permission to abandon ship
Not yet !
Rear tube ready!
Hold on tight
Cap at 80!
Fire!
Right away where we died
A torpedo!
All starboard!
Cut in two
If you need a Chef, Mr. Tyler
i am your man
It's okay ?
Trigger drowned
He did not deflate
Neither do you, Mr. Tyler
On going hat
Abandon ship
This film is dedicated to
Allied sailors and officers
who risked their lives
to seize ENIGMA
during the Battle of the Atlantic
MAY 9, 1941. ENIGMA MACHINE
AND CODES ENTERED ON THE U-110
BY HMS BULLDOG AND HMS AUBRETIA
October 30, 1942.
WEATHER FIGURE SEIZED ON U-559
Par hms petard
JUNE 4, 1944. ENIGMA MACHINE
AND CODES ENTERED ON THE U-505
BY US NAVY